<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Go on Bayesian Blogs</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/go/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Go on Bayesian Blogs</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 19:43:13 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/go/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Crash in Fiber&#39;s BodyParser Due to Unvalidated Large Slice Index in Decoder</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/fiber-crash/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 19:43:13 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/fiber-crash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the past couple months (albeit very sporadically), I have been getting my feet wet in the world of fuzzing. I have been alluding to &amp;ldquo;fuzzing experiments&amp;rdquo; in my recent blogs - and I am happy to state that my experiments have yielded a result! I found an exploitable crash in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gofiber/fiber&#34;&gt;Fiber&lt;/a&gt; framework. When using Fiber&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;Ctx.BodyParser&lt;/code&gt; to parse form data containing a large numeric key that represents a slice index (e.g., &lt;code&gt;test.18446744073704&lt;/code&gt;), the application crashes due to an out-of-bounds slice allocation in the underlying schema decoder. This issue was discovered in Fiber v2.52.8 and has been fixed in v2.52.9. This issue has been assigned &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gofiber/fiber/security/advisories/GHSA-qx2q-88mx-vhg7&#34;&gt;CVE-2025-54801&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Ran Free SAST Tools on chi and Found a GHSA</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ghsa-vrw8-fxc6-2r93/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2025 09:11:02 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ghsa-vrw8-fxc6-2r93/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/go-chi/chi/security/advisories/GHSA-vrw8-fxc6-2r93&#34;&gt;GHSA-vrw8-fxc6-2r93&lt;/a&gt; is a Host Header Injection issue in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/go-chi/chi&#34;&gt;chi framework&lt;/a&gt; which allows arbitrary redirect to any domain while redirecting slashes. I did not receive a CVE for this finding &amp;ldquo;Given the lower impact (can&amp;rsquo;t be exploited in browser or email client)&amp;rdquo; (verbatim from the maintainers) - which I can agree with to some extent. I will say though, that lower impact vulnerabilities should also get CVEs, else there would be no CVSS &amp;ldquo;low&amp;rdquo; score CVEs. My slight disagreement is probably more influenced by me wanting CVEs to my name than a technical outlook. Having said that, GHSAs are pretty recognized too, and in these parts, we take what we get.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
