<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bayesian Blogs</title>
    <link>https://baishya.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Bayesian Blogs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 23:54:28 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://baishya.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cocktails</title>
      <link>https://baishya.xyz/cocktails/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 23:54:28 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://baishya.xyz/cocktails/</guid>
      <description>Sour Monk 1 oz Old Monk 0.5 oz bourbon 1 oz lemon juice 0.75 oz simple syrup Garnish: Amarena Cherry </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://baishya.xyz/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 16:49:25 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://baishya.xyz/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello friend! Thank you for stopping by! If you have stumbled upon this page, you might be looking to know more about me. My name is Anuraag Baishya. Some of my friends like to call me &amp;ldquo;Bayesian&amp;rdquo; which is why this blog is titled Bayesian Blog.&#xA;By day I work on Palo Alto Networks&amp;rsquo; PSIRT team as a Sr. Staff Product Security Engineer, dealing with all things PSIRT such as handling reports and incidents, working with our engineers to investigate said reports and help them fix bugs, releasing advisories, and any other operations you would imagine a PSIRT personnel would need to handle.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tales from my Product Security Job Hunt: Part 2, Preparation</title>
      <link>https://baishya.xyz/posts/interview-prep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 21:51:34 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://baishya.xyz/posts/interview-prep/</guid>
      <description>This is part 2 of my interview experience and preparation series, where I will talk about how I prepared for the interviews. Check out part 1 where I talk more about the process and types of interviews here&#xA;As I mentioned in my previous post, this is catered to my search criteria, which was:&#xA;Experience: Mid-level (~4–5 years of experience) Role: Product Security / Application Security Even within the roles I was looking for, different openings had slightly different requirements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tales from my Product Security Job Hunt: Part 1, Interview Types</title>
      <link>https://baishya.xyz/posts/types-of-interviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 16:12:46 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://baishya.xyz/posts/types-of-interviews/</guid>
      <description>After spending 4 amazing years at Adobe, I recently decided it was time to take the next step in my career. I was fortunate to interview with several companies that varied in terms of their domain, size, or the maturity of their security processes.&#xA;Many of those whom I informed about my decision and/or my interviews were interested in knowing what the process was like and how I prepared. After answering the same questions a few times, I thought it would be helpful to potential job seekers if I documented my experiences.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hack the Box — PC, but automated</title>
      <link>https://baishya.xyz/posts/htb-pc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 20:05:09 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://baishya.xyz/posts/htb-pc/</guid>
      <description>PC is an easy Linux box that has a grpc service and a vulnerable version of an application running on it. While doing this box, I had gone to the forums for a hint, and I saw a comment that said something along the lines of “I wrote a script that can solve this box”. I found this quite intriguing and decided to write a script that could solve the box myself.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
