<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Php on Bayesian Blogs</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/php/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Php on Bayesian Blogs</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 19:37:34 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/php/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I Ran Free SAST Tools on OpenEMR and Found a CVE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/cve-2025-30161/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 19:37:34 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/cve-2025-30161/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CVE-2025-30161 is a stored XSS vulnerability in the bronchitis form component of OpenEMR. It allows anyone with access to edit a bronchitis form to inject malicious javascript payload into the form and run these payloads in the context of other users including administrators.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am a big proponent of open source static analysis engines like &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/semgrep/semgrep&#34;&gt;Semgrep&lt;/a&gt; and tools like &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.snyk.io/scan-with-snyk/snyk-code&#34;&gt;Snyk Code&lt;/a&gt; that provide a free tier. One of the biggest selling point for both Semgrep and Snyk is that they allow writing your own rules. I have written many Semgrep rules at my job or otherwise and have found the rule language easy to learn and understand, while also providing very powerful features such as taint tracking and autofixing. Snyk&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.snyk.io/scan-with-snyk/snyk-code/snyk-code-custom-rules/create-custom-rule&#34;&gt;custom rule&lt;/a&gt; support is currently in preview as of the time of writing. Both Semgrep and Snyk also have a set of pre-built rules. In the Semgrep world they are called community rules and can be found in this &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/semgrep/semgrep-rules&#34;&gt;repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
